nwpubliclands.net 2013-04-16

# Privacy Policy - Discover Your Northwest

Home  >  Privacy Policy| [](http://www.facebook.com/pages/Discover-Your-Northwest/315700667061)[](http://twitter.com/#!/DYNW)[](http://www.flickr.com/groups/experience_your_northwest/) [](http://www.addthis.com/bookmark.php?v=250&pub=dlindau)  
---|---  
  
At Discover Your Northwest, we value your support and are committed to protecting your privacy. Our site is a safe environment for anyone who shops or makes a donation.

**Information We Collect**  
We collect personal information from you only when it is specifically and knowingly provided by you. When you make a purchase or donation online, we ask for your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, and credit card information. When you sign up for our email newsletters, or use our "Tell-a-Friend" email feature on our product pages, we collect names, email addresses, and topics of interest if indicated. This information is collected and maintained in a secure database.

It is our policy not to sell, trade, or rent your personal information to anyone without your advance permission. We will not share your personal information with any third party, except to contracted service providers acting on our behalf or unless ordered to do so by a court of law. We reserve the right to change our policy at any time. If we choose to change our policy, you will be given the option to remove your name from our database. 

**Child Privacy**   
We do not knowingly solicit or collect personally identifiable information online from children under the age of 13. If we learn that a child under the age of 13 has submitted personally identifiable information online, we will take all reasonable measures to delete such information from our databases and to not use such information for any purpose (except where necessary to protect the safety of the child or others or as required by law).

**Use of Personal Information**   
Employees of Discover Your Northwest, or contracted service providers acting on our behalf, will have access to your personal information only to fulfill orders or conduct appropriate business. We will use your information to process your transaction and to verify credit card data. We will use your mailing address to ship your order and may occasionally send emails with information about northwest public lands, special events, volunteer opportunities, donation drives, and product offerings. It is our policy to discontinue contacting any person upon oral or written request to us, our fundraising agents, or other official representatives. All emails sent will have a simple unsubscribe option, as required by law.

**Use of Non-Personal Information**   
We also collect various kinds of basic, non-personal information. This includes total number of visitors, pages viewed, referring websites, and other non-identifying statistics that contain no personal information and cannot be used to gather such information. We use this aggregate information to pursue partnerships that further our mission, improve the quality of our website, and to make your experience on our website as smooth as possible.

**Protecting Your Information**   
Our online order processing system allows you to make safe purchases and donations. We use GeoTrust to provide you with the latest encryption technology, Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), to insure that no one can read your information as it travels to our ordering system. To verify security, click on the GeoTrust link on pages that solicit personal information, such as the checkout pages of our online store.

This website is tested and certified daily by McAfee Secure to pass the FBI/SANS Internet Security Test. The "live" McAfee Secure mark appears only when a website's security meets the highest security scanning standards of the U.S. government and all major credit card companies. Please note, however, that no system is failsafe and that we cannot guarantee that the information submitted to, maintained on, or transmitted from our systems will be completely secure.

**Credit Card Information**   
Our online credit card verification system is provided by CyberSource, which collects your name, address, phone number, credit card number, and expiration date in order to process your transaction. Their encryption technology offers the highest level of security available on the Internet today. They have state-of-the-art firewalls and other security technology in place to protect the confidentiality of your transactions. _Your credit card information is not stored in our system._

**Use of Cookies**   
To allow you to keep merchandise information in your basket as you shop our Online Store, we utilize "cookies," which record your order information in your computer's web browser. The order "cookies" we use are only used to process your order. Most browsers are configured to automatically accept "cookies," though you can disable this feature. However, you will not be able to shop our online store unless your web browser has this feature turned on.

If you would like to place an order without configuring your web browser to accept "cookies," please call your order in to us at (877) 874-6775.

**Creating An Account**   
We also offer you the option of setting up an account to make your checkout faster each time you shop. This way we can remember your shipping and billing information each time you login. _Credit card information is not stored in our system and must be entered with each transaction._

**How to Contact Us  
**To contact us regarding your personal information, or request that we correct, add, or remove your information from our system, you can reach us at:

**Discover Your Northwest**  
164 S. Jackson St.  
Seattle, WA 98104  
Phone: (877) 874-6775  
E-Mail: customer service
